arnoldclark.com 2017-06-06

# Cookies policy | Arnold Clark

  * Information we Collect
  * Data Security
  * How We Use Cookies
  * What Cookies We Use

We hope you will enjoy using the Arnold Clark Automobiles Limited website, and we want to make sure your experience is as safe and useful as possible. Here you can find out how our website works, what data we collect from you and how it is used to optimise your experience.

## The information that we collect

To make an online Service, MOT or Repair booking, we require your Name, Contact Information and Vehicle Details. You can specify if you would like this information to be stored in a cookie, so as to avoid repeat typing in subsequent visits. When you search our New Car Special Offers or Used Car Stock Locator we may store information on the vehicles you searched for in a cookie so that we can personalise site content.

When you enter one of our competitions, we require your name, e-mail address and daytime telephone number so we can contact the winner. Unclaimed prizes may be offered to other competition entrants within a stated time period at the promoter's discretion. We monitor visitor usage patterns to help us continually improve the site.

We may track what type of vehicles you view so that we can make suggestions and personalise site content.

Occasionally, we may use your e-mail address to send you information about changes to this website or to inform you of new products available from companies within the Arnold Clark group. We will ask you for permission to do so. If, at any time, you no longer wish to receive this information, please send a written request to direct.marketing@arnoldclark.co.uk.

## Data Security

You should be aware that the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## Disclosing Your Information

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * If we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Arnold Clark Automobiles Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of the Arnold Clark group, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 
  * If you use our "Live Chat" function via our partner, Contact At Once, where your information may be collected, used and stored as part of our "Live Chat" service your personal information will be shared with Contact at Once.

## How we use cookies

Arnold Clark Automobiles Limited use cookies to help improve our websites and make your browsing experience more useful, more relevant and tailored to you. In order to comply with recent legislation and in the interests of transparency, we have updated our privacy policy to give you clearer information on the way we use technology such as cookies and how they affect your privacy.

Cookies are small text files, placed on your hard disk by a web page server. They are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

Our cookies do not collect any data that could be used to personally identify you. What we will do is use encrypted information gathered from the cookies to improve your online experience with Arnold Clark Automobiles Limited.

Some of the cookies we use will expire after you close the browser window. These are called session cookies. Some cookies last longer than this, because they are used to identify return visits to the Arnold Clark Automobiles Limited website. Please note that cookies do not harm your computer or any software you may have.

Arnold Clark Automobiles Limited recommends that you accept the setting of cookies, as we use them to:

  * Customise elements of our websites' layout and content, and test different designs of our websites to improve your experience.
  * Recognise when a user has visited before, meaning we can see how many unique visits we receive. We can then make sure the websites are easy to use and have enough capacity.
  * Remember your preferences and settings, such as text size and language.
  * Recognise your device so you don't have to provide the same information during your visit, or on subsequent visits.
  * Help us identify errors and resolve them effectively.
  * Establish what information is relevant to you while you are browsing our websites.
  * Collect statistical, anonymous information about how our visitors use/interact with our digital services so we can improve them.
  * Learn which parts of our websites are most popular and improve them.
  * See how effective our online messages are.

However, you can choose to decline cookies by changing your browser settings.

  * **Session** cookies are deleted when you leave our websites. They help keep track of your progress so you don't have to enter the same information more than once.
  * **Persistent** cookies stay on your device after your browsing session has ended. They will remember settings, preferences and details for the next time you use the websites.
  * **First party** cookies are set by the website owner, i.e. Arnold Clark Automobiles Limited.
  * **Third party cookies** are set by other parties, such as Google and Twitter.
  * **Necessary cookies** are required for the operation of our website. 
  * **Performance or analytical cookies** allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies** are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, for example, remember your preferences. (for example, your postcode in Find a Dealer search). 

## What cookies we use and why

### Necessary Cookies

Cookie Name  |  Type  |  Purpose   
---|---|---  
Searchcookie | Session, First Party | This helps us remember what you searched for, from page to page. The website would not function correctly without this cookie enabled.  
JSESSIONID | Session, First Party | This helps us remember what you searched for, from page to page. The website would not function correctly without this cookie enabled.  
  
### Session Cookies

Cookie Name  |  Type  |  Purpose   
---|---|---  
AC_srch | Session, First Party | This cookie remembers what you searched for from page to page. To use our search function, this cookie needs to be enabled.  
49a2c522799  
ce817e01  
b8c4aeb886  
9f8 |  | This is an admin cookie set by the CMS.  
Session | Session, Third Party (Towquest) | By setting and using session cookies throughout our booking process we are able to get you back to your booking session if you happen to move away to a different page or even if you close your browser. This session cookie means that next time you return to the booking process your previous session will have been saved.  
LoginStatus | Session, Third Party (Towquest) | If you have a registered account with us we are able to determine if you are logged in to our website using cookies. This will save you time on your next visit to the website as we will already know your details. By setting a cookie to remember your details, for your next visit, we are able to personalise your user experience and you won't have to re-enter your details every time you visit.  
LoginName | Session, Third Party (Towquest) | We want you to feel welcome at the Arnold Clark Automobiles website so we use cookies to remember who you are if you have a registered account with us. By saving cookies, based on you account details, we can make your next visit to our website personal to you, by welcoming you back to the website by name.  
  
### Performance Cookies

Cookie Name  |  Type  |  Purpose   
---|---|---  
Mixpanel | Persistent, Third party (Mixpanel, Inc) | When visiting some parts of our website, we may set this cookie which enables us to collect information in real time about the way users interact with our site. For more information about how Mixpanel may use this information, visit: [www.mixpanel.com/privacy/](https://www.mixpanel.com/privacy/)  
Google Analytics (_utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz) | Persistent, Third party (Google) | These enable the function of Google Analytics. This software helps us take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers, response to marketing activity and browsing times. That anonymous information helps us to improve the website and your browsing experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant. The data stored by these cookies can be seen only by the relevant teams at Arnold Clark and Google and never shows any confidential information. For more information about how Google may use this data - visit: //www.google.com/policies/privacy/  
Crazy Egg | Persistent | This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, details of which can be found by following this link. //www.crazyegg.com/privacy  
Get Clicky cookies, (first_pv_ , _jsuid) | Persistent, Third party | These cookies allow us to track visitors to the website using Get Clicky. We can use visitor information on which pages were visted, how frequently, and for how long to improve the website and the user experience. The data stored by these cookies can be seen only by the relevant teams at Arnold Clark and Get Clicky, and never shows any confidential information. //getclicky.com/terms  
Auto Trader Dealer Display Retargeting | Persistent, Third party | This cookie is used by our advertising supplier Auto Trader to identify users of the Arnold Clark website when they subsequently visit autotrader.co.uk. This enables Auto Trader to target these users with display advertising specific to Arnold Clark. The data stored anonymously identifies a user as having visited www.arnoldclark.com.  
  
### Functional Cookies

Cookie Name  |  Type  |  Purpose   
---|---|---  
showroom cookie, showroomsns | Persistent, First Party | This allows you to use the shortlisting feature. It means we can remember which cars you added to the shortlist as you move from page to page. If you add cars to the shortlist, this information will be remembered while you browse the site, and when you return to the site.  
  
### Third Party Cookies

Cookie Name  |  Type  |  Purpose   
---|---|---  
Google Maps cookies, (SID, HSID, NID, SAPSID, SSID, PREF) | Mostly session, Third Party | We embed Google maps on various pages within our website. The cookies set by embedded Google maps appear to detect your preferences and record usage of Google maps. Read their privacy policy here: //www.google.com/policies/privacy/  
_utma, | Persistent, Third Party | Refers to the number of times you have visited our website and the first and the last visit times.  
_utmb | Persistent, Third Party | Google Analytics cookies that contain timestamps of time you enter and leave our website.  
_utmc | Session Third Party | Google Analytics cookies that contain timestamps of time you enter and leave our website.  
_utmz | Persistent, Third Party | Google Analytics cookie that tracks which search engine you have used to come to this website, which keyword(s) you used to find the website, which link(s) you have clicked on within the website and where you were located when you clicked that link.  
  
To find out even more about cookies, visit [www.aboutcookies.org/](https://www.aboutcookies.org/)

## IP Addresses

We may collect information about your computer in the form of server logs, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions, and does not personally identify any individual.

## Links

Our website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

## Changes to our Privacy & Cookies Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy & cookies policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.
